JOE: Life events and transitions
indicate change, and as we have discussed
previously, change is often very difficult
for individuals on the autism spectrum.
An individual with autism needs to
be prepared for any changes caused
by life events and transitions making
the process easier for them to handle.
BETH: The planning process to prepare
an individual with autism, for a life
event or transition, should cover
every aspect of that change and how
it will impact the individual, making
the process easier to deal with.
Also, the needs of everyone involved
and those supporting the individual
must be considered, considering how
they are impacted by the life event
and the emotional needs of all affected
by the change in the situation.
JOE: Seeking the support of others
especially professionals can help to
support everyone concerned and they can
become a good asset to have on board
when in the process of transition.
BETH: A psychotherapist or counsellor
or another trusted professional such
as a social worker may be able to offer
guidance and support and a range of
strategies that may help with change
associated with a specific life event or
transition that may impact the family.
JOE: Support groups and online
communities may also be a good source
of help offering their own experiences
and guidance, giving insights into how
to approach the transition process.
BETH: Informal support networks
can also be helpful directly and
indirectly helping with more general
support that might be needed.
Families should not be afraid of seeking
help when they need it to make the
changes associated with life events
and transitions progress more smoothly.